A Finding Aid to the Gene Davis Papers, 1920-2000, bulk 1942-1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.davigene
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 1942-1990; Series 6; 5.2 Linear feet Boxes 7-11, 17-18, OV 20
  Series includes annual reports of museums, published arts-related calendars, auction catalogs, brochures from organizations with which Davis had some affiliation, exhibition announcements and invitations, exhibition catalogs, magazine articles, newspaper clippings, newsletters, posters, press releases, and other published material. Most exhibition announcements and catalogs are for Davis’s solo exhibitions or group shoes in which his work was shown, although a few documents related to exhibitions of other artists are also found. A 1988 publication of proceedings from an Artists’ Congress of the Coalition of Washington Artists is also found.
  Photocopies are found of some printed material, most of which were assembled by Percy North in her bibliographic research on Davis after his death. When original copies of this material was not found in the collection, photocopies were integrated with other like materials during processing.
  - Annual Reports, 1958-1968 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1972-1979 (Box 7, Folder 2-4)
  - Annual Reports, 1981-1985 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - Arts Calendars, 1973-1984 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Auction Catalogs, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Books (Box 7)
    - Art in Washington Calendar and Diary, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Donald Judd: Complete Writings 1959-1975 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Gene Davis, Edited by Donald Wall, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Miro 1940-1955, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - The Washington DC Art Review, by Frank Getlein and Jo Ann Lewis, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Brochures (Box 7)
    - General File, 1946-1981 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1963-1976 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Guggenheim Fellowship, 1968-1974 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - The Madeira School, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Pace Editions, circa 1976 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, circa 1950-1985 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1950-1966 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Oversized announcement in Box 17
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1967-1971 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1972-1980 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1950-1990 (Box 7, Folder 25-26)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1950-1954 (Box 7, Folder 25-26)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1955-1958 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 8-10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 11-13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 14-15)
    Oversized catalog in Box 17
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 18-22)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 23-24)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 26-27)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 28-29)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Flyers Related to Film and Video, circa 1970-1982 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Magazine Articles, circa 1942-1990 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Magazine Articles, 1942-1949 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    Includes published poems by Davis from 1942-1943
  - Magazine Articles, 1952-1954 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Magazine Articles, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Magazine Articles, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Magazine Articles, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Magazine Articles, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Magazine Articles, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Magazine Articles, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 26-27)
  - Magazine Articles, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Magazine Articles, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Magazine Articles, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Magazine Articles, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Magazine Articles, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Magazine Articles, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Magazine Articles, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Magazine Articles, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Magazine Articles, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Magazine Articles, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Magazine Articles, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Magazine Articles, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Magazine Articles, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Magazine Articles, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 13-15)
    Oversized magazines in Box 17
  - Magazine Articles, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
    Oversized magazine in Box 17
  - Magazine Articles, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 18-19)
  - Magazine Articles, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Magazine Articles, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Magazine Articles, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper Clippings, circa 1945-1985 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1945-1947 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1950-1955 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    Oversized clippings in Box 18
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1956-1957 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1960-1962 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Oversized clippingsin Box 18
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 20-21)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 22-24)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 26-27)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Newsletters, 1967-1979 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Newsletters, 1980-1989 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Periodicals, Mark Twain Journal, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Periodicals, Right Angle, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Phonograph Album with Cover Art by Davis, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    Oversized record in Box 18
  - Postcards, circa 1969-1984 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Posters, circa 1967-1984 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    Oversized posters in OV 20
  - Press Releases, circa 1967-1989 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Printing Proofs of Artwork Reproductions, circa 1972-1987 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Proceedings, Artist's Congress, Coalition of Washington Artists, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Program, Parrish Art Museum Gala, circa 1989 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Stag Films, circa 1970 (Box 11, Folder 41-42)
  - Oversized Exhibition Announcement from Box 7, folder 20 (Box 17)
  - Oversized Exhibition Catalog from Box 8, folder 14 (Box 17)
  - Oversized Magazines from Box 10, folders 14-15 (Box 17)
  - Oversized Magazines from Box 10, folder 17 (Box 17)
  - Oversized Magazines from Box 10, folders 18-19 (Box 17)
  - Oversized Clippings from Box 10, folders 25 and 27 (Box 18)
  - Oversized Clippings from Box 11, folders 1-3 (Box 18)
  - Oversized Clippings from Box 11, folders 5-8 (Box 18)
  - Oversized Clippings from Box 11, folders 9, 10, and 12 (Box 18)
  - Oversized Clippings from Box 11, folders 18-19 (Box 18)
  - Oversized Clippings from Box 11, folder 26 (Box 18)
  - Oversized Phonograph Album from Box 11, folder 34 (Box 18)
  - Oversized Posters from Box 11, folder 36 (Box OV 20)
- Photographs, 1920-2000; Series 7; 3.8 Linear feet Boxes 11-15, 17, OV 19
  Snapshots are grouped in sets of photographs that were shot or processed at the same time wherever possible. Some of these sets include scattered individual shots not relating to the general subject matter named in the folder heading. Where photographs with similar content or from the same group of photographs have been divided between the albums and loose photographs, similar folder headings are used in both locations. Negatives are filed with corresponding prints wherever possible as well, but not all negatives have been matched to their prints in the series arrangement. Where negatives are known to have no corresponding prints in the collection, it is noted in the folder list.
  Photographs documenting Davis’s storage facility from 1985, presumably taken for estate assessment purposes, are filed with the Business and Estate Records. Photographs used in Steven Naifeh’s monograph on Davis are filed with drafts of the book’s manuscript in series 5, Writings. Photographs reproduced in a memorial photo album are filed with series 1, Biographical Material. Moving images containing footage of students and art classes are found in series 8, Artwork.
  Photographs include personal photographs of Gene and Florence Davis and their families, portraits of Gene Davis, photographs of Gene Davis with artworks and working in the studio, Davis’ art classes and students, installations of site-specific works, conceptual and video works, exhibition openings, and photographs of artwork, both installed in exhibitions and individually photographed. Also found are three disassembled photograph albums with similar content. Photographic media include prints, contact sheets, negatives, Polaroid prints, slides, and transparencies. Scattered 4x5” Copy negatives appear to have been created for the catalog to the 1987 memorial exhibition at the Smithsonian American Art Museum, and envelopes containing these negatives sometimes provide additional identifying information not on the original print.
  Images of Gene Davis are scattered throughout the series, either alone or in groups, and other people pictured are not typically identified. Where people are identified on the original photographs, their names are included in the folder list below. Among those identified in photographs are Harry Truman, John L. Lewis, J. Edgar Hoover, Walter Hopps, Jacob Kainen, Ed McGowin, Douglas Davis, Jane Livingston, Joan Mondale, and Bob Woodward. Three photograph albums that were disassembled upon accession of the collection are filed at the beginning of the series. Many of the photographs in these albums are from groups of prints filed elsewhere in the series. Album photographs include portraits of Davis, childhood photographs, Davis working as a journalist and model early in life, snapshots from travels and social gatherings, Davis’s Washington, D.C. home, Davis in his studio, art classes, installations of site-specific works, and artworks.
  Loose photographs comprise the remainder of the series and include personal photographs and art-related photographs. Personal photographs include portraits of Gene Davis and Florence Coulson Davis, family photographs, and snapshots taken over a period of twenty years showing the Davis’s with family and friends at home and traveling abroad. Portraits and snapshots are followed by several sets of photographs showing art classes, art students, and models for classes presumably taught by Davis. Other art-related photographs include openings for Gene Davis exhibitions, visits to other museum and gallery exhibitions, installations of Davis’s site-specific works, and photographs of the 1969 “Giveaway” event. Snapshots of Davis’s studio, some with Davis pictured and some without, are also found.
  Photographs of artwork include prints, slides, transparencies, and Polaroid prints of drawings, paintings, and video art by Davis, shot individually and also shown installed in specific exhibitions. Prints are typically identified by title and date and sometimes collection, and some prints contain information about their creation or reproduction. Also found are exhibition views of installed works spanning Davis’ career. Photographs of artwork and exhibition views are black and white prints unless otherwise indicated in the folder list. Among the exhibition views are four videocassettes (VHS) of the 1987 retrospective at the Smithsonian National Museum of American Art.
  - Disassembled Photograph Album 1 (Box 11)
    - Childhood Photographs of Gene Davis, circa 1920-1939 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Davis Working as a Model for Detective Stories, circa 1940 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Davis Working as a Journalist, circa 1945-1965 (Box 11, Folder 45)
      With Harry Truman, John L. Lewis, and J. Edgar Hoover
    - Portraits of Davis, circa 1950-1975 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Travel Snapshots and Photographs of Gene and Florence Davis, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Exhibition Openings, 1959-1975 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Davis with Artworks, circa 1959-1972 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Davis Working, circa 1970-1985 (Box 11, Folder 50)
      See also Disassembled Photograph Album 3, and Studio photographs
    - Studio and Art Classes, 1968-1971 (Box 11, Folder 51)
      See also Art Classes, Students, and Models and Studio Photographs
    - Installations of Site-Specific Works, 1969-1979 (Box 11, Folder 52)
      Includes color slides of “Giveaway” and “Niagara” at ArtPark, and black and white prints of Franklin’s Footpath, Grass Painting, and others.
    - Installation of Magic Circle at the Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Disassembled Photograph Album 2 (Box 12)
    - Artwork, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Florence Davis and Walter Hopps pictured
    - Artwork, 1968-1972 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Artwork, 1973-1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Exhibitions, circa 1969-1987 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Installation of The Sentinels at the Willard Hotel, Washington, D.C., 1981 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - House, 1970-1978 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Disassembled Photograph Album 3 (Box 12)
    - Portraits of Davis, circa 1977-1983 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Portraits of Davis, circa 1978 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Davis Teaching, circa 1976-1979 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Davis Working in the Studio, circa 1973-1983 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Davis with Jacob Kainen, circa 1979 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Davis with Artwork, circa 1982 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Davis with Artwork, by Mary Swift, circa 1982 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Davis with Artwork, by Percy North, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Davis with Artwork, by Ellen Page Wilson, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Exhibition at Walker Art Center, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 16-17)
    - Exhibition Opening, Max Protetch Gallery, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      Davis pictured with Bob Woodward
    - Exhibition Openings, Corcoran Gallery, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Exhibition Opening, Unidentified, circa 1980 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Installations of Site-Specific Works, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Installation of Site-Specific Works, Niagara, ArtPark, Lewistown, NY, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 22-23)
    - Installation of Site-Specific Works, Black Yo-yo at Cranbrook Academy of Art, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Artwork, Self-Portraits, circa 1982 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Personal Photographs (Box 12)
    - Portraits of Gene Davis, circa 1930-1945 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Portraits of Gene Davis, circa 1950-1985 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Portraits of Gene Davis by Joe Cameron (circa 1969), 2000 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Portraits of Gene Davis by Azar Hammond, circa 1975 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Portraits of Gene Davis by Rosalind Solomon, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 30)
      Oversized photographs in OV 19
    - Portrait of Gene Davis by Deborah Haynes, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Portrait of Gene Davis by Ellen Page Wilson, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Portraits of Florence Coulson Davis, circa 1940-1990 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Portraits of Gene and Florence Davis, circa 1960-1980 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Family of Gene Davis, circa 1940-1960 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Family of Florence Coulson Davis, 1983; 1936-1960 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Gene Davis as White House Correspondent, circa 1946-1947 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Wedding and Honeymoon, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Dartmouth College Graduation, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Dupont Theater and Indonesian Embassy Exteriors, Washington, D.C., circa 1980; Negatives only (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Autographed Portraits of U.S. Presidents, circa 1945-1963 (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Home, Friends, and Family Snapshots, 1964-1971 (Box 12, Folder 42-45)
    - Home, Friends, and Family Snapshots, circa 1974 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Home, Friends, and Family Snapshots, circa 1976; Polaroids (Box 12, Folder 47-48)
    - Home, Friends, and Family Snapshots, circa 1977-1979 (Box 12, Folder 49-52)
    - Home, Friends, and Family Snapshots, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Home, Friends, and Family Snapshots, circa 1972-1985 (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - Travel Snapshots (Box 13)
      - Jamaica, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Italy and Germany, 1969 April (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - England and France, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - France, Italy, and England, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
      - France, Italy, and Spain, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 5-7)
      - New York City, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Austria, circa 1980 (Box 13, Folder 9-12)
      - Unidentified Travel Snapshots, circa 1975-1985 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Art Classes, Students, and Models (Box 13)
    See also moving images in series 8, Artwork
    - Art Classes, Students, and Models, circa 1960-1985 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Art Classes, Students, and Models, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      Set stamped May 1968 contains photograph labeled "View of fires on 14th Street during race riots of 1968"
    - Art Classes, Students, and Models, Skidmore College, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      Many of the photographs are labeled with names of those pictured; full names mentioned include Bob Reed, Sharon Duffy, and Karen Smiley.
    - Art Classes, Students, and Models, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 17)
      Contains photograph of Gene Davis behind a video camera
    - Art Classes, Students, and Models, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 18)
      Two photographs labeled with names Azar Hammond and Steve Ludlum.
    - Art Classes, Students, and Models, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 19)
      Two photographs labeled with names Ann Purcell and Benita Berman
    - Art Classes, Students, and Models, circa 1979 (Box 13, Folder 20-21)
      One photograph labeled with name Steve Kruvant.
    - Art Classes, Students, and Models, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Art Classes, Students, and Models, circa 1980 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Art Classes, Students, and Models, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Exhibition Openings (Box 13)
    See also Disassembled Photograph Albums 1, 2, and 3
    - Dupont Theater Lobby, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Watkins Gallery at American University, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Jefferson Place Gallery, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Jefferson Place Gallery, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Unidentified Exhibitions, circa 1968-1985 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Max Protetch, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, Walk-through with Joan Mondale and Jane Livingston, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - National Museum of American Art, Smithsonian Institution, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Exhibition Visits, circa 1969-1982 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Exhibition Visits, Documenta 5, Kassel, Germany, 1972; Negatives only (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Exhibition Visits, Walker Art Center, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Exhibition Visits, Zoo, circa 1979 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - "Giveaway" at the Mayflower Hotel, Washington, D.C., 1969 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    Gene Davis pictured with Douglas Davis, Ed McGowin, and others; see also Box 11, folder 52 for color slide of event; see file of related documentation in series 8, Artwork.
  - Installation of Site-specific Work (Box 13)
    See also Disassembled Photograph Albums 1 and 2
    - Unidentified Site, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Neiman Marcus in Bal Harbour, Florida, 1971; 1977 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Franklin's Footpath, Philadelphia, PA, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Magic Circle at the Corcoran Gallery of Art, Washington, D.C., 1975 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Niagara at ArtPark, Lewistown, NY, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Black Yo-yo at Cranbrook Academy of Art, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Ferris Wheel at the Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Studio Photographs, 1970; 1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Studio Photographs, circa 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Davis and assistants pictured
  - Studio Photographs, circa 1960-1982 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Davis pictured
  - Studio Photographs, circa 1985 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Snapshots possibly taken at the time of Davis's death
  - Photographs of Artwork (Box 14)
    - Abstract Impressionist Paintings, undated (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
    - Collages, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Drawings, undated (Box 14, Folder 10-13)
    - Drawings from Child and Man Exhibition, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Drawings and Paintings in Smithsonian National Museum of American Art Exhibition, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 15-16)
    - Gene Davis Signature Boxing Trunks and Robe, 1983; Color prints (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Micropaintings, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Micropaintings, undated; Color print (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Neon Sculpture The Sentinels, circa 1981; Color print (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Paintings, undated (Box 14, Folder 21-31)
      Oversized photographs in box 17
    - Paintings, undated; Color prints (Box 14, Folder 32-33)
    - Paintings, undated; Color transparencies (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Paintings, undated; Color slides (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Plank Paintings, undated (Box 14, Folder 36-37)
  - Photographs of Artwork (Box 15)
    - Plan for Proposed Grass Painting, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Video Art Stills and Exhibition View, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Watercolors, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Artwork by Others, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Exhibition Views (Box 15)
    - Axiom Gallery, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Brooklyn Museum of Art, circa 1982 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Charles Cowles Gallery, 1983-1986 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Cleveland Museum of Art, circa 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, circa 1979 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, Ferris Wheel, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Denver Art Museum, 1984; Color prints (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Fischbach Gallery, 1966-1977; Black and white prints and color slides (Box 15, Folder 12)